<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Michael's Blog</title><link href="https://mikeeryan.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://mikeeryan.github.io/blog%5Cfeeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://mikeeryan.github.io/blog/</id><updated>2019-02-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Online Courses Part 2</title><link href="https://mikeeryan.github.io/blog%5Csixth-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-02-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Michael Eryan</name></author><id>tag:mikeeryan.github.io,2019-02-17:/blog\sixth-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this post I talk about my experience with a premier technology learning platform.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pluralsight.com/" target="_blank"&gt; Pluralsight &lt;/a&gt; is a popular learning platform among technology departments of large companies. It is a subscription-based online school so make sure you check if your company already has a partnership with them before buying a personal subscription. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I have taken two "paths" on Pluralsight: &lt;a href=" https://app.pluralsight.com/paths/skills/python" target="_blank"&gt; "Python" &lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://app.pluralsight.com/paths/skills/the-scrum-framework" target="_blank"&gt;"Using the Scrum Framework."&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python path is a collection of eleven courses split into Beginner, Intermediate and Advanced. Out of all the courses, I have to admit, that the best are the three courses by Robert Smallshire and Austin Bingham. These courses are "Python fundamentals," "Python beyond the basics," "Advanced Python" that follow their books "The Python Apprentice," "The Python Journeyman," and "The Python Master" available from this &lt;a href=" https://leanpub.com/u/abingham" target="_blank"&gt; publisher here. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three courses by Smallshire and Bingham are the best on Python that I have found. They describe their approach as a "spiral" with higher level courses going deeper into the previously discussed topics. I think it's a great approach that allows to acquire a deep fundamental understanding of this wonderful programming language. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other courses in the Python path range from very basic introductions to "type along without understanding" to testing and, at least to me, did not have that much value. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pluralsight also has "soft-skill" courses as well. I took the &lt;a href="https://app.pluralsight.com/paths/skills/the-scrum-framework" target="_blank"&gt;"Using the Scrum Framework"&lt;/a&gt; path to quickly gain an understanding of Agile and Scrum. If you wish to learn that too, I do recommend you read the official guides to understand the basics first. Then you can take this course which will give you a thorough understanding and plant a vision in your head of a typical Scrum environment. The course author Jeremy Jarrell has done a great job of creating a realistic environment that will help you identify with the Scrum team members. This will help you to demystify Scrum and grant you confidence that you will succeed in such an environment in the future. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="schools"></category></entry><entry><title>Online Courses Part 1</title><link href="https://mikeeryan.github.io/blog%5Cfifth-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-02-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Michael Eryan</name></author><id>tag:mikeeryan.github.io,2019-02-10:/blog\fifth-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this post I describe my experience with online schools.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nowadays there are a lot of choices for online schools or &lt;a href=" https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massive_open_online_course" target="_blank"&gt; MOOC's.&lt;/a&gt;
How to choose the right one for you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I would recommend examining their business model before digging into the course content. Check if they charge per course/certificate or a monthly subscription. Compare based by estimating your total long term costs. Also consider how the content is made available to you. Will you have to keep up with the classes on tight schedules or are the schedules more flexible? Think what would work the best for you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, after reviewing several schools, I settled on Udacity and been with them for the past three years. What attracted me was that their content was freely available. I could watch their videos for free at my own pace. I did not pay anything until I was ready to take the plunge and enroll in their nanodegree program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when I enrolled in the &lt;a href=" https://www.udacity.com/course/data-analyst-nanodegree--nd002" target="_blank"&gt; Data Analyst Nanodegree&lt;/a&gt; they charged a monthly subscription fee. So, the final cost depended on how quickly I could submit the final projects for each module of the degree. I took advantage of this model and studied all the courses before enrolling. That way when I enrolled, I paid only for a few months during which I was mainly working on the projects and did not have to study a lot of new material. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understandably, a little bit later Udacity modified this model to generate more review. Today they charge a flat fee for each fixed length term of their nanodegrees. There are now recommended deadlines for the completion of each module but it's still pretty flexible because there are no live classes or weekly assignments. As long as you turn in the projects more or less on time and do not fall behind too much, you will graduate successfully. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can still study in advance of enrolling but you will not save any money by graduating early because you have to pay a flat fee. This is how my experience was for my second certificate - &lt;a href=" https://www.udacity.com/course/machine-learning-engineer-nanodegree--nd009t" target="_blank"&gt;Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend you to review the content of the modules closely. Udacity has expanded their roster of nanodegrees quite a bit. Inevitably, they nerfed some of the programs and moved some of their content to other programs. Also, there is overlap between the programs, so choose wisely to save money and time (which is also money anyway). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today, Udacity has almost 200 free courses for you to study at your own pace. I have completed 30+ of them so far, and I wish I had more time to complete many more. Definitely take advantage of this free content before you enroll in any Nanodegree program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good Luck and Have Fun!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="schools"></category></entry><entry><title>Publishers and Books</title><link href="https://mikeeryan.github.io/blog%5Cfourth-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-02-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Michael Eryan</name></author><id>tag:mikeeryan.github.io,2019-02-03:/blog\fourth-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this post I mention some of my favorite publishers and books in the Data Science field.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are many great publishers and books on Data Science. I would like to mention the ones I have benefitted from the most. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first one is &lt;a href="https://www.manning.com" target="_blank"&gt;Manning Publishing.&lt;/a&gt; What I like about their books is how well the chapters are organized. At least the ones I have read, all had similar structures, good code listings with comments, tables and screenshots. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a great introductory level book using Python - &lt;a href="https://www.manning.com/books/introducing-data-science" target="_blank"&gt;Introducing Data Science, 2016&lt;/a&gt; It covers the main concepts of data science, machine learning, distributed computing, NoSQL and Graph databases, text analytics, data visualization and so on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just read this preface. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;It’s in all of us. Data science is what makes us humans what we are today. No, not the computer-driven data science this book will introduce you to, but the ability of our brains to see connections, draw conclusions from facts, and learn from our past experiences. More so than any other species on the planet, we depend on our brains for survival; we went all-in on these features to earn our place in nature. That strategy has worked out for us so far, and we’re unlikely to change it in the near future.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;But our brains can only take us so far when it comes to raw computing. Our biology can’t keep up with the amounts of data we can capture now and with the extent of our curiosity. So we turn to machines to do part of the work for us: to recognize patterns, create connections, and supply us with answers to our numerous questions. The quest for knowledge is in our genes. Relying on computers to do part of the job for us is not—but &lt;strong&gt;it is our destiny&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn't it sound like Dataism manifesto?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The other publisher I like is &lt;a href="https://www.packtpub.com" target="_blank"&gt;Packt.&lt;/a&gt; They have a great variety content and their books do not all look alike. They have great deal on eBooks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had to pick just one book to explain Machine Learning, I would undoubtedly pick &lt;a href="https://www.packtpub.com/big-data-and-business-intelligence/python-machine-learning-second-edition" target="_blank"&gt;Python Machine Learning, 2017&lt;/a&gt;  by the great Sebastian Raschka and Vahid Mirjalili. After getting through a whopping 500+ pages I had only one complaint - I wish it were longer! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great content covering from the simplest algorithms to complex neural networks, supervised and unsupervised learning. Explains well what embeddings are and how back propagation works - hint: there is no sorcery involved. Uses scikit-learn and Tensorflow, and even walks you through how to create a simple predictive web app using Flask. I wish they follow up with a similarly great book on Reinforcement Learning. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="books"></category><category term="publishers"></category></entry><entry><title>Third Post</title><link href="https://mikeeryan.github.io/blog%5Cthird-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-01-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-01-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Michael Eryan</name></author><id>tag:mikeeryan.github.io,2019-01-27:/blog\third-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the third post that demonstrates a simple table.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the third post that demonstrates a simple table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Column Header&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Column Header&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Row 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Data 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Row 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Data 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content><category term="table"></category></entry><entry><title>Second Post</title><link href="https://mikeeryan.github.io/blog%5Csecond-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-01-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-01-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Michael Eryan</name></author><id>tag:mikeeryan.github.io,2019-01-26:/blog\second-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the second post of a series of posts. It will show an example jupyter notebook.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post contains an embedded sample jupyter notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Sample-jupyter-notebook"&gt;Sample jupyter notebook&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="#Sample-jupyter-notebook"&gt;&amp;#182;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="input"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;In&amp;nbsp;[1]:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
    &lt;div class="input_area"&gt;
&lt;div class=" highlight hl-ipython3"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;This better work.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="output_wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="output"&gt;


&lt;div class="output_area"&gt;

&lt;div class="prompt"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="output_subarea output_stream output_stdout output_text"&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;This better work.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope it worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 

&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="jupyter"></category></entry><entry><title>First Post - Welcome</title><link href="https://mikeeryan.github.io/blog%5Cfirst-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-01-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-01-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Michael Eryan</name></author><id>tag:mikeeryan.github.io,2019-01-25:/blog\first-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first post on my blog.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first post on my blog.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="python"></category><category term="pelican"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry></feed>